Alessandro Rossini

Researcher and lecturer in software engineering

© Oslo, Norway ம் alessandrorossini.org ⊠ me@alessandrorossini.org

Born 22 Dec 1980, Italian citizen, Norwegian resident, male, single.

I am detail-oriented, organised, and goal-oriented. During recent years, I have conducted extensive research and development in the field of software engineering, with particular emphasis on model-driven engineering and cloud computing.

Experience

Research Scientist, Department of Networked Systems and Services, SINTEF, Oslo, Norway	Nov 2012-Feb 2017
Part-time Lecturer, Department of Electrical and Electronic Eng., Bergen University College, Norway	Jan 2012-Jul 2012
Guest Researcher, Department of Computer Science, Universidad Autónoma de Madrid, Spain	Feb 2011-May 2011
Research Fellow, Department of Informatics, University of Bergen, Norway	Jan 2008-Jan 2012
Software Engineer, Integrator, Bergen, Norway	Jun 2007-Dec 2007
Software Engineer, ZeroNotice, L'Aquila, Italy	Aug 2005-May 2007
Software Engineer (Intern), IgTechnology (now Indra), Roma, Italy	May 2005-Jul 2005
Part-time Trainer, Training agency Assodonna, Pescara, Italy	Oct 2004-Mar 2005

Projects

ARCADIA, a framework for the development of highly-distributed applications	Jan 2014-Feb 2017
PaaSage, a model-based framework for the specification and execution of cross-cloud applications	Nov 2012-Nov 2016
Broker@Cloud, a cloud brokerage framework for continuous quality assurance and optimisation	Nov 2012-Feb 2016
STWT , a framework for the specification of simulators for systems of partial differential equations	Jan 2013-Dec 2014
DPF , a diagrammatic specification framework founded on category theory and graph transformation	Jan 2008-Jan 2012
ZNF , an open source framework for the development of enterprise web applications	Aug 2005-May 2007

Management

Group Chair , Instance Model Ad Hoc group of the OASIS TOSCA standard	Oct 2015-Present
Technical Committee Member, OASIS TOSCA standard	Mar 2014-Present
Internal Project Manager and Work Package Leader, EU-funded projects (see Projects above)	Jan 2013-Present
Panel Chair, PhD panel of the Faculty of Mathematics and Natural Sci., University of Bergen, Norway	Mar 2010-Feb 2011
Founding Member, OpenLUG Linux User Group of L'Aquila, Italy	Nov 2001-Oct 2007

Organisation

Organising Committee Member: FM 2015 Doctoral Symposium, CSB 2014, NordiCloud 2013

Program Committee Member: CF 2016, MULTI 2016, MMHS 2016, PROCON 2016, ESOCC 2016, MULTI 2015, MMHS 2015, MULTI 2014, MMHS 2014, CSB 2013, SLE 2012

Reviewer: CAEE, SoSyM, Computing, NIK 2013, MODELS 2013, JSME, MODELS 2012, ECMFA 2012, AGTIVE 2011, ICMT 2011

Education

Philosophiae Doctor (Ph.D.), Department of Informatics, University of Bergen, Norway	Jan 2008-Dec 2011
Master of Science (M.Sc.), Department of Computer Science, Università degli Studi dell'Aquila, Italy	Jan 2004-Dec 2006
Bachelor of Science (B.Sc.), Department of Computer Science, Università degli Studi dell'Aquila, Italy	Sep 1999-Dec 2003

Languages

Mothertongue: Italian, Fluent: English, Norwegian, Spanish

Publications

30+ publications in peer-reviewed conferences and journals.